<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:webfeeds="http://webfeeds.org/rss/1.0" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Ryluiiwan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Ryluiiwan</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:27:06 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Aug 2017 21:38:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/about/</guid>
      <description>👉 This is ryluiiwan Former TK influencer marketing professional (a mere salesperson), aspiring to learn Digital Marketing skills and knowledge (that&amp;rsquo;s the current plan) for a career transition. Studied Data Science and Big Data Technology in university, with some basic programming knowledge and analytical thinking. After graduation, through various twists and turns, I stumbled into marketing and promotion. I enjoy eating, sleeping, strolling in parks, stargazing, moonwatching, reading, and having imaginative conversations with friends.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="-this-is-ryluiiwanhttpryluiiwancom">👉 This is <a href="http://ryluiiwan.com">ryluiiwan</a></h2>
<p>Former TK influencer marketing professional (a mere salesperson), aspiring to learn Digital Marketing skills and knowledge (that&rsquo;s the current plan) for a career transition. Studied Data Science and Big Data Technology in university, with some basic programming knowledge and analytical thinking. After graduation, through various twists and turns, I stumbled into marketing and promotion. I enjoy eating, sleeping, strolling in parks, stargazing, moonwatching, reading, and having imaginative conversations with friends. I have a strong interest in exploring the essence and patterns of things.</p>
<p>Hope to become a person with inner strength.</p>
<h2 id="-wishing-well">🥂 Wishing Well</h2>
<p><strong><em>Personal Life</em></strong>, hoping to maintain both physical health and inner peace, to live a long life (and hope this isn&rsquo;t just a dream)</p>
<p><strong><em>Career Development</em></strong>, do meaningful things (for myself and others), mutual achievement and win-win is what I believe to be the best principle in social relationships, continue to deeply cultivate expertise in a specific field</p>
<h2 id="books-read-in-2024">✍Books Read in 2024</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26878124/">My Brilliant Friend: Neapolitan Novels Book 1</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30384422/">The Surrender Experiment</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26757680/">The Painted Veil</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26895993/">Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36132802/">It&rsquo;s Okay Not to Forgive</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36096300/">Why Fish Don&rsquo;t Exist</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35627242/">Our Inner Conflicts</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36084340/">Destiny</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/27127895/">Those Things About the Ming Dynasty (Extended Edition) (9-Volume Set)</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/10345553/">For N</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26425831/">Stoner</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36018994/">Smart People&rsquo;s Personal Growth</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36104107/">The Lychees of Chang&rsquo;an</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36316908/">Miss Pear&rsquo;s Time with Herself</a></li>
</ul>
<h2 id="books-read-in-2023">🖐Books Read in 2023</h2>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26958752/">Pretending to Be Normal: Living with Asperger&rsquo;s Syndrome</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35771718/">Please Draw Love</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35031587/">The Silent Cry</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36243264/">Bed, Sofa, My Life</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35503551/">Blue</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/4180711/">The Psychology of Procrastination</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36401716/">Today&rsquo;s Weather is Perfect for Quitting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35581777/">Living Consciously: A Journey Beyond Self</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/1775691/">The Road Less Traveled: A New Psychology of Love, Traditional Values and Spiritual Growth</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26896878/">The Razor&rsquo;s Edge</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/33440237/">Feel the Wind</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35876121/">The Almanack of Naval Ravikant</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26575679/">What I Talk About When I Talk About Running</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36082424/">The Oyster with Shell is the Adult&rsquo;s Heart</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30188003/">Why Elites Are Time Masters</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/36073906/">When We Cease to Understand the World</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/27054340/">A Man Called Ove</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30358363/">Running on Empty: Overcome Your Childhood Emotional Neglect</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/35523099/">Feminism from Zero</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/33422386/">The Cafe at the Edge of the World</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E03: Starting a New Year, A Journal Entry of What I Did</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/05/s01e03-starting-a-new-year-a-journal-entry-of-what-i-did/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2025/01/05/s01e03-starting-a-new-year-a-journal-entry-of-what-i-did/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Doing nothing&amp;rdquo; best describes this week&amp;rsquo;s state. Strangely, although I really enjoy this slightly boring state where I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do anything, I can&amp;rsquo;t contentedly enjoy it, always feeling that I should use this time to do something, that I can&amp;rsquo;t stop learning and improving. I constantly bounce between &amp;rsquo;let&amp;rsquo;s enjoy now and think later&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;regret doing nothing.&amp;rsquo; The brain can be deceptive, words are beautifully woven lies,</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>&ldquo;Doing nothing&rdquo; best describes this week&rsquo;s state. Strangely, although I really enjoy this slightly boring state where I don&rsquo;t have to do anything, I can&rsquo;t contentedly enjoy it, always feeling that I should use this time to do something, that I can&rsquo;t stop learning and improving. I constantly bounce between &rsquo;let&rsquo;s enjoy now and think later&rsquo; and &lsquo;regret doing nothing.&rsquo;</p>
<p>The brain can be deceptive, words are beautifully woven lies, forgiveness like love is temporary, nothing is eternal. Sometimes I think such evil thoughts. Amid expectations for the new year, there&rsquo;s also fear mixed in. Leaving a place, starting a new life - I fear unfamiliar environments, fear meeting not-so-kind bad people, fear life&rsquo;s balance tipping from the neutral end gradually toward the bad end.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m still diligently reading <a href="https://www.douban.com/doubanapp/dispatch?uri=/book/26986954">The Story of a New Name: Neapolitan Novels 2</a>, and it&rsquo;s infuriating to see the comments section constantly attacking Lenu (one of the main female characters, from whose perspective the novel unfolds). In a novel about female friendship, the comment section is filled with malicious comments. I wonder why people are so keen on judging others&rsquo; inner thoughts and behaviors, and this judging desire seems similar to a &ldquo;desire to control&rdquo; that can be seen in every corner of the internet.</p>
<h2 id="dining-and-chatting">👭Dining and Chatting</h2>
<p>Monday evening, I met friends for dinner and chat, celebrating the new year early. That afternoon, the lazy sunlight felt warm on my clothes, making me feel wrapped in something soft. I finally walked that road behind my house that I&rsquo;d never taken before. I don&rsquo;t know why I was so busy this past year, leaving my neighborhood and surroundings so vague in my mind. That road is quiet, almost empty, a wide and lonely street with half the one-way road available for cycling. Going forward is a long downhill stretch - on a downhill, you just need to maintain direction and you&rsquo;ll keep moving forward. Taking this road to my usual movie theater greatly reduces travel time. There&rsquo;s a school at the end of the road, with an abandoned building across from it. No one knows its history; everyone just passes by.</p>
<p>For convenience and safety, I use &ldquo;Snoopy&rdquo; as my name for deliveries. Walking back home via that back road to get a package, I stared at the three characters &ldquo;史努力&rdquo; (a misspelling of Snoopy in Chinese) on the delivery bag and fell into contemplation, then laughed helplessly. Sometimes, typos can bring us infinite joy.</p>
<p>In the evening, I met friends for Korean BBQ and chat, discussing everything from work to recent movies, eventually landing on characters from Jin Yong&rsquo;s novels. We confusedly mixed up various character relationships, arguing for quite a while, alternating between confusion and clarity, laughing until my sides hurt. It&rsquo;s always joyful dining and chatting with friends who share similar senses of humor and frequencies. I&rsquo;ve started rewatching <a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/33464863/">Hospital Playlist</a> recently, and I hope that when I&rsquo;m forty, I&rsquo;ll still have a group of friends to eat, drink, and laugh with.</p>
<h2 id="jealousy-is-an-emotion">🐏Jealousy is an Emotion</h2>
<p>I&rsquo;m not sure why I feel this way, as I don&rsquo;t have strong awareness of my emotions. Sometimes, I can&rsquo;t even distinguish these emotions. Most people have attached an extremely negative label to the word &ldquo;jealousy,&rdquo; seeing it as evil, like wanting someone to do well but not too well, a mindset of silent competition.</p>
<p>Last month, I happened upon a used bookstore and browsed some children&rsquo;s picture books, including one about emotions. The emotion family consists of happiness, sadness, fear, jealousy, shame, envy, surprise, anger, disgust, and love. In this picture book, jealousy was described as a &ldquo;little vinegar bottle&rdquo; - perhaps sour in taste, but as long as it doesn&rsquo;t harm anyone, jealousy is just another emotion.</p>
<p>Perhaps influenced by reading <a href="https://www.douban.com/doubanapp/dispatch?uri=/book/26986954">The Neapolitan Novels</a>, where Ferrante, through Lenu&rsquo;s inner world, describes extensive psychological activities of Lenu&rsquo;s silent comparison and jealousy toward Lila. Yet this doesn&rsquo;t affect my fondness for both Lenu and Lila. Human nature has too many complex facets; judging what&rsquo;s good or bad in black-and-white terms is too simplistic. Judge actions, not thoughts.</p>
<h2 id="the-lucky-cat-is-a-fish">😺The Lucky Cat is a Fish</h2>
<p>At the supermarket this week, I visited the ornamental fish section and immediately spotted two white fish with duck-bill-like heads. The yellow label on the tank showed their nickname as <strong>Lucky Cat</strong>. Writing this now, I think: maybe I can get rich this year too. Later I checked Wikipedia; its scientific name is <a href="https://zh.wikipedia.org/wiki/%E7%B4%85%E5%B0%BE%E9%AF%B0">Red-tailed Catfish</a>.</p>
<p>The supermarket is decorated more festively than last time. After growing up, perhaps because I can no longer receive New Year&rsquo;s money, I don&rsquo;t look forward to the New Year much. I might face relatives&rsquo; intrusive questions about salary and relationships. In the village, boundaries between people suddenly disappear, with occasional privacy invasions behind warm greetings. I have complex feelings about this - I like the warmth but hate privacy intrusions. People should maintain some distance; these boundaries must exist.</p>
<p>Suddenly, while writing, I&rsquo;m getting sleepy. Don&rsquo;t want to continue writing. Recently reading the Neapolitan Novels, I want to train my writing skills. Ferrante&rsquo;s writing, though direct, is delicate and comfortable to read. I love this writing style. I really hope I can earn enough money to travel to Italy someday; I want to see her Naples with my own eyes, make a pilgrimage. Well, suddenly I have a new goal for the new year.</p>
<h2 id="books-films-and-audio">🎨Books, Films, and Audio</h2>
<p>This week I mainly watched <a href="https://www.douban.com/doubanapp/dispatch?uri=/book/26986954">The Story of a New Name: Neapolitan Novels 2</a> and <a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/33464863/">Hospital Playlist</a>.</p>
<p>The rest of the time I was sleeping. Ten hours every day. I&rsquo;m dizzy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E02: A Week of Lying Flat and Doing Sit-ups Repeatedly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/29/s01e02-a-week-of-lying-flat-and-doing-sit-ups-repeatedly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:26:42 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/29/s01e02-a-week-of-lying-flat-and-doing-sit-ups-repeatedly/</guid>
      <description>This month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been deeply troubled by noise from upstairs neighbors - heavy and sometimes sharp footsteps constantly coming from above. Whether at six or seven in the morning or midnight, you never know when that unique &amp;ldquo;noise&amp;rdquo; will suddenly appear, greatly reducing sleep quality. Already sensitive to sound, I&amp;rsquo;m becoming increasingly so, and am currently seeking various solutions.
Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Maugham&amp;rsquo;s The Painted Veil before bed. Though I thought it would take forever to finish, I completed it in just a few evenings.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This month, I&rsquo;ve been deeply troubled by noise from upstairs neighbors - heavy and sometimes sharp footsteps constantly coming from above. Whether at six or seven in the morning or midnight, you never know when that unique &ldquo;noise&rdquo; will suddenly appear, greatly reducing sleep quality. Already sensitive to sound, I&rsquo;m becoming increasingly so, and am currently seeking various solutions.</p>
<p>Recently, I&rsquo;ve been reading Maugham&rsquo;s <a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26757680/">The Painted Veil</a> before bed. Though I thought it would take forever to finish, I completed it in just a few evenings. Maugham&rsquo;s observation and portrayal of human nature is truly remarkable. I noted down some favorite passages about the world&rsquo;s ugliness and how humans create beauty through art, life, and their creations, and about women&rsquo;s perceptions of men&rsquo;s love.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;m actually more engrossed in <a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26878124/">The Neapolitan Novels</a>. <del>Although I&rsquo;m only halfway through the first book</del>, (I persisted and finished it on December 29th, and even dreamed about Lila and Lenu that night), I think this will be my book of the year. I love Ferrante&rsquo;s portrayal of the studious Lenu, and the clever, brave Lila through Lenu&rsquo;s eyes. I love their friendship of mutual pursuit, subtle competition, but ultimately care and love for each other.</p>
<h2 id="my-brilliant-friend">My Brilliant Friend</h2>
<p>My journey with <a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26878124/">The Neapolitan Novels</a> began when I accidentally discovered the TV series <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/bangumi/play/ss68648">My Brilliant Friend</a> on Bilibili. At first, all the names blended together, and the Naples neighborhood where Lila and Lenu lived appeared desaturated and violent - I wasn&rsquo;t sure what it was about. Though I almost gave up watching, after sorting out the relationships between characters, I became deeply engaged. It&rsquo;s truly an excellent work, and I&rsquo;ve become an enthusiastic advocate, recommending it to friends.</p>
<p>After finishing Season 3 of <a href="https://www.bilibili.com/bangumi/play/ss68650">My Brilliant Friend</a>, I discovered the original novel had long been in my WeChat Reading bookshelf, added after recommendations from podcasts or book bloggers, like many other unread books there. Honestly, the TV series is quite faithful to the plot. But Ferrante&rsquo;s writing has a certain flowing power, with deep analysis of Lenu&rsquo;s inner world, love for Lila, and occasional dark humor. She frequently mentions <strong>the dissolution of boundaries</strong> in her work. Each time I encounter this phrase, I find it somewhat difficult to comprehend. Looking through the comments section, I found someone who shared Zhang Yueran&rsquo;s writing about this dissolution of boundaries, explaining Ferrante&rsquo;s views on limitations, pressure, and disappearance as a form of refusal.</p>
<p>On December 24th, I changed my blog&rsquo;s background to a still from My Brilliant Friend, finding it extremely satisfying.</p>
<h2 id="neither-lying-flat-nor-hustling-successfully">Neither Lying Flat Nor Hustling Successfully</h2>
<p>Nearly two months after leaving my job, I still haven&rsquo;t decided what to do next. I&rsquo;ve never been goal-oriented or good at planning. Usually, I follow the mindset of <strong>crossing bridges when I come to them, taking one step at a time, going wherever life takes me</strong>. Though I occasionally worry and feel anxious, walking on an unplanned path makes me curious about what will happen next, where fate will lead me, experiencing the push of destiny. After all, the unknown is truly fascinating. Two years ago, I never imagined I&rsquo;d be in a city 2,000 kilometers from home; a year ago, I didn&rsquo;t think I&rsquo;d stick to a job for over a year and save some money. Back then, I was poor and lost. If there was any luck, it was in accepting reality and continuing to move forward.</p>
<p>The reality is that at night, seeing my savings gradually decrease, I question myself: &ldquo;Where did all this money go, why does it disappear so quickly?&rdquo; With these questions in mind, I started learning some skills on Coursera. I should learn skills that can earn money, allowing future me to lie flat longer - early retirement would be ideal, as working is so inhuman, better avoided if possible.</p>
<p>On the afternoon of December 27th, I reopened <a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30384422/">The Surrender Experiment</a>, which I had previously read one-third of. Sometimes, reading books is also about timing. Michael Singer&rsquo;s discussion of surrendering to life&rsquo;s flow involves letting go of the self and letting things happen naturally. This seems similar to &ldquo;going with the flow.&rdquo;</p>
<h2 id="the-market-is-paradise-on-earth">The Market is Paradise on Earth</h2>
<p>In the summer of 2021, while sharing an apartment with friends in Shijiazhuang, we wanted to cook hot pot together and went to a nearby market. How could a clean, bright, and orderly market not be paradise? Neatly arranged tomatoes, irresistible cilantro - a market where you can find almost anything. My fondness for markets comes from observing life. Here you can observe freely, selection requires observation and comparison. Sometimes when unable to distinguish good from bad, I observe other shoppers, their selection criteria, which stalls are busier, which have more variety, which have fresher produce - all requiring keen observation.</p>
<p>On the morning of the 27th, I cycled to the supermarket. Checking the weather forecast showing 19℃, I thought it wouldn&rsquo;t be too cold, but the wind made it hard to keep my eyes open. I love observing everything in my visual range except people - the unnamed trees by the bus stop with leaves scattered yellow on the ground, bare branches shrinking. The pink flowers by the pedestrian bridge have lost their former lustre, becoming dim. In Shenzhen&rsquo;s winter, only a few flowers and trees and unemployed me are hibernating. The tall, lush trees across the road constantly remind me of this fact.</p>
<p>The supermarket is already decorated for the New Year - red clothes, large posters hanging from the ceiling, festive music. In the blink of an eye, a year has passed, and these decorations suddenly remind me of when I first came here this year.</p>
<p><strong>Beautiful and happy things always come from life itself</strong>. This is a deep realization this year. I often feel I&rsquo;m suffering, unhappy, waiting for some day or year when my life will suddenly become happy and bright, living in the past while imagining the future, ignoring the present life, thinking things will be better later. My life should be composed of countless <!-- raw HTML omitted --> - the past was once <!-- raw HTML omitted -->, and the future will be <!-- raw HTML omitted --> later. So I just need to live well in the present.</p>
<h2 id="books-films-and-audio">Books, Films, and Audio</h2>
<p>Some recently finished and current reads, movies, and articles</p>
<h3 id="reading-recent-reads">⭐Reading: Recent Reads</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/30384422/">The Surrender Experiment</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26878124/">My Brilliant Friend: Neapolitan Novels 1</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26986954/">The Story of a New Name: Neapolitan Novels 2</a>  🔋</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="films--tv-recent-watches">📺Films &amp; TV: Recent Watches</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/36401937/">The Wrong Thing</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/bangumi/play/ep755419">Toxic Lawyer</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/bangumi/play/ss40523">The Durrells Season 1</a>  🔋</li>
</ul>
<h3 id="videos-youtubebilibili">🎨Videos: YouTube/Bilibili</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=g1tCB67lp4U&t=2283s">📚2 Hours Real-Time Study / Piano Music / Christmas Night in Tokyo Streets / Pomodoro (25+5) / STUDY WITH ME ✨</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1oHC3YzEAK/">VLOG｜NYC Daily Life/Last Week of Fall Semester/Christmas Preparation/Making Gingerbread House/Solo Cooking</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1rS4y1b7cU/">【Yuuka Sagawa】Japanese Posture Master&rsquo;s Exercises for Hunchback, Face Slimming, Shoulder &amp; Neck</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1dT42167f9/">How Social Media Affects Your Health</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1ZV411a7Fc/">How to Make Even the Most Ordinary Life Interesting</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1jE421w7D8">Stop Using GPT! Claude 3.5 is the Strongest AI【Beginner Tutorial】</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="others">📝Others</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://polebug.github.io/2024/12/18/law_of_attraction/">Reading Notes and Thoughts on &lsquo;Law of Attraction: How to Use Psychological Suggestion to Fulfill Wishes&rsquo;</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.coursera.org/projects/google-ads-beginner">Google Ads for Beginners</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>S01E01: Recent Days - A Journal Entry of Daily Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/22/s01e01-recent-days-a-journal-entry-of-daily-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:07:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/22/s01e01-recent-days-a-journal-entry-of-daily-life/</guid>
      <description>Everything feels like it&amp;rsquo;s been put on fast-forward, and suddenly it&amp;rsquo;s late December. All that happened this year has started to blur, as if covered by a layer of dust. Getting older and addicted to fragmented information has left my brain rusty and locked, requiring occasional taps on the head to remember what year it is. Since my teenage years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worried about potentially developing Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s. Back then, I occasionally wrote on my little WeChat public account, creating a collection called &amp;ldquo;Memoirs of a Potential Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Patient,&amp;rdquo; where I would sporadically record things, hoping I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Everything feels like it&rsquo;s been put on fast-forward, and suddenly it&rsquo;s late December. All that happened this year has started to blur, as if covered by a layer of dust. Getting older and addicted to fragmented information has left my brain rusty and locked, requiring occasional taps on the head to remember what year it is. Since my teenage years, I&rsquo;ve worried about potentially developing Alzheimer&rsquo;s. Back then, I occasionally wrote on my little WeChat public account, creating a collection called &ldquo;Memoirs of a Potential Alzheimer&rsquo;s Patient,&rdquo; where I would sporadically record things, hoping I wouldn&rsquo;t forget.</p>
<p>This year, work disrupted my life rhythm, and I barely picked up a pen to record my life: what movies I watched, what books I read, what insights I had. I even forgot how to write - sometimes spending ages trying to write certain characters on paper, and sometimes still ending up with wrong characters despite long contemplation. I can&rsquo;t help but wonder how my language abilities have deteriorated to this state, deteriorated so badly it frightens me. I can&rsquo;t even write simple holiday greetings without searching online. When language becomes this impoverished, there&rsquo;s hardly any feeling left - one becomes just an empty and numb person.</p>
<p>It was probably September when I saw a YouTuber <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=OmyfB513E1s">Reysu</a> sharing a video about journaling. He taught an all-in-one journaling method that isn&rsquo;t too burdensome for someone like me who often works sporadically. I can start recording anytime without forcing myself to write daily. So I bought a diary and began recording my daily life. September had just a few entries with large blank spaces; October was filled for most of the month with some gaps; November had entries for every day plus journal entries; December is still ongoing with daily records and even more journal entries. Now I&rsquo;ve developed a habit of frequently recording my life, able to trace back to what special things happened on any given day. It&rsquo;s quite a nice experience, and I really want to recommend it to everyone I know.</p>
<h2 id="1-eat-well-sleep-well">1. Eat Well, Sleep Well</h2>
<p>After experiencing a toxic workplace environment, being marginalized, and reaching emotional exhaustion, I finally recognized - though always late - that I had met some wonderful colleagues who became friends I could dine and watch movies with. This marks the end of my brief one-year work chapter.</p>
<p>After leaving, I started taking care of my health and seeing traditional Chinese medicine doctors. I stayed at my sister&rsquo;s place for half a month, developed a habit of eating breakfast, never missing any of the three daily meals. Remarkably, I - a <code>motion sickness wreck</code> - stopped getting carsick. It turns out many problems can be solved by simply <code>eating properly</code>. Since childhood, I&rsquo;ve been plagued by motion sickness, often feeling like dying when riding in vehicles, which made me hate traveling. This troublesome issue was ultimately solved in the simplest way, though I might still get motion sickness occasionally. Well, eat well!</p>
<p>Recently, I was diagnosed with <code>fatigue syndrome</code> by a traditional Chinese medicine doctor. I was constantly dreaming while sleeping, couldn&rsquo;t wake up properly, and needed 9-10 hours of sleep to get up, always feeling tired and lacking energy afterward. This month, I started recording my sleep time in my diary. Except for one or two nights when I couldn&rsquo;t sleep due to heavy footsteps from upstairs neighbors, I&rsquo;ve been sleeping more than 8.5 hours every day, partly due to winter&rsquo;s arrival and partly due to my blood deficiency and extreme lack of energy. Well, sleep well, no more staying up late!</p>
<h2 id="2-nature-heals-all">2. Nature Heals All</h2>
<p>My home is far from parks, requiring at least two subway transfers to reach one. During the week, I visited a huge park for a walk. My park-visiting style is the simplest - just walking, going wherever my feet take me, often completely losing my sense of direction, just moving forward. I love the dappled shadows created by sunlight filtering through leaves onto walls or ground - enough to make me stop and appreciate. This park, probably due to its location in the city center, has very few bird species, with rarely any bird calls heard.</p>
<p>The park is full of people running and cycling, focused on enjoying themselves. Later, somewhere in the park, I saw two adorable active cats, like little &ldquo;mountain kings&rdquo;: a friendly tabby cat and a slightly timid black-and-white cat. I played with them for a while, watching them dart around. I wonder what humans are like in a cat&rsquo;s world.</p>
<p>Walking through a grove of trees, I happened to see a tree that was dead from top to root. I was about to walk away but turned back for another look. That dead tree had sprouted new buds from its branches, green shoots emerging from the withered body - how powerful and tenacious is the force of life.</p>
<h2 id="3-books-films-and-audio">3. Books, Films, and Audio</h2>
<p>Recently, my time has been entirely my own, allowing more time for media consumption.</p>
<h3 id="reading-recent-reads">✍Reading: Recent Reads</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26895993/">Peak: Secrets from the New Science of Expertise</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26757680/">The Painted Veil</a>   ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/27204805/">The Neapolitan Novels</a></li>
<li><a href="https://book.douban.com/subject/26815948/">The Power of Now</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="films--tv-recent-watches">📌Films &amp; TV: Recent Watches</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/36154853/">All the Good Things</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/36712987/">Breaking Hell</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/25851655/">Your Lie in April</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/28427782/">My Brilliant Friend Season 1</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/30395843/">My Brilliant Friend Season 2</a>  ✅</li>
<li><a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/35051880/">My Brilliant Friend Season 3</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="videos-youtubebilibili">🎨Videos: YouTube/Bilibili</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1UExyefEyt">Comprehensive Guide to Self-Learning Art</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.bilibili.com/video/BV1zw41187Dn">Ginkgo: Living Until Forgotten by Death</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=xR5-0XDkwU0&t">My Obsidian Setup: The King of Note Taking Apps</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=fxnVADG7H7w">how I would learn Digital Marketing in 2025</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=MPTBT4-r4Fs&t=2881s&ab_channel=AbaoinTokyo">📚2 Hours Real-Time Study / calm piano / Tokyo Tower sunset / Pomodoro (25+5) / STUDY WITH ME 🗼</a></li>
</ul>
<h3 id="podcasts-xiaoyuzhouapple-podcasts">🎧Podcasts: Xiaoyuzhou/Apple Podcasts</h3>
<ul>
<li><a href="https://www.xiaoyuzhoufm.com/episode/6720836fbad346ebe6399017">E37 Fish Don&rsquo;t Exist</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.xiaoyuzhoufm.com/episode/663ac13e13426298925c9853">S5E8 Lu Yu Talks with Zhang Chun | To Live Long, I Made This Decision</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.xiaoyuzhoufm.com/episode/65f0ed0179f1b490bfb042a5">S5E1 Lu Yu Talks with Zhan Qingyun | Believing in Day-to-Day Effort, What RBG Taught Me</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.xiaoyuzhoufm.com/episode/65f86f2c67649570791b3b74">vol.03 Possessing Real Energy: Discussing How to Become Yourself</a></li>
<li><a href="https://www.xiaoyuzhoufm.com/episode/660b4d8f2d9eae5d0a7ad4a0">vol.04 Q&amp;A: Solutions to Some Fundamental Anxiety Issues</a></li>
</ul>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>In November, I Started My 24th Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/07/in-november-i-started-my-24th-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 12:11:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/2024/12/07/in-november-i-started-my-24th-year/</guid>
      <description>Last month on the 8th was my 24th birthday. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel much about it, nor did I have any sense of ceremony to celebrate. Even my mom forgot about my birthday. I feel that age is just a number to me - I can still eat ice cream, splash in puddles, observe little crabs in the supermarket, discover cute little things, and do things that elementary school kids do.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Last month on the 8th was my 24th birthday. I didn&rsquo;t feel much about it, nor did I have any sense of ceremony to celebrate. Even my mom forgot about my birthday. I feel that age is just a number to me - I can still eat ice cream, splash in puddles, observe little crabs in the supermarket, discover cute little things, and do things that elementary school kids do. Growing up perhaps means allowing yourself to experience double happiness - both adult joys and childlike pleasures.</p>
<p>This year I don&rsquo;t have any specific wishes either, just want to live fully in the present moment, experience, and feel.</p>
<h2 id="1-at-24-experience-and-feel-all-beautiful-things">1. At 24, Experience and Feel All Beautiful Things</h2>
<p>Last month I watched an interesting Japanese drama called <a href="https://movie.douban.com/subject/30291583/">We Are Made of Miracles 僕らは奇跡でできている (2018)</a>, which gave me great inspiration. The male lead is a university professor teaching animal behavior. In class, he would pose intriguing questions like &ldquo;Why didn&rsquo;t the turtle wake up the sleeping rabbit in the race?&rdquo; and &ldquo;Why do zebras have stripes?&rdquo; When students ask him, he always replies &ldquo;I don&rsquo;t know.&rdquo; It suddenly occurred to me that many questions don&rsquo;t have standard answers, nor absolute right or wrong. Under the intense exam-oriented education since childhood, I had even lost the imagination to think expansively and had no curiosity or desire to explore other forms of life in this world. So one random morning when I woke up, I carefully listened to several different bird calls downstairs. Observing the small things around us can really help us temporarily break free from the framework of rules set by human society and enter a broader world.</p>
<p>After watching some interviews and listening to some podcasts where everyone emphasizes being yourself, saying things like you must do what you like in life and so on - this broad concept, but &ldquo;I&rdquo; simply can&rsquo;t find what I like to do. What I like to do is doing nothing, but is that &ldquo;being yourself&rdquo; in the conventional sense? One day while listening to a podcast, I heard a view I quite agree with - we&rsquo;ve given absolute authority to language, and within this rule framework defined by language, it feels like too many things are restricted. They give definitions to people, divide classes and hierarchies, and have a set of rules about what is meaningful and valuable. But I feel that our existence itself is living, we&rsquo;ve been being ourselves since birth until now. Not being able to find what you like to do, not finding your talent or interest, it&rsquo;s not a big deal. Just being alive is an impressive existence. You don&rsquo;t necessarily have to trap yourself in certain narrative patterns.</p>
<p>I often feel I&rsquo;m a strange person who can&rsquo;t understand many rules in the human world, staying outside of crowds. My counselor told me this is also a part of me, respect and maintain your uniqueness. Previously I really couldn&rsquo;t understand what it meant to truly &ldquo;love yourself.&rdquo; When I heard those words, I felt loving yourself means first accepting all of yourself - accepting that you&rsquo;re not so smart, accepting your quirks, accepting your mediocrity, accepting your imperfections, stop being harsh on yourself. When you&rsquo;re feeling down, hug yourself, comfort yourself by saying: you&rsquo;re already doing great, no matter what you do, I will support you unconditionally, I will always be your best friend. This year I read some psychology books and had several counseling sessions, which has helped me treat myself more gently. Previously I was always troubled by feeling like I didn&rsquo;t have best friends growing up, I was always alone - alone going to movies, alone going to hospitals, alone doing almost everything. But I can always get along well with myself, so I decided that I am my best friend.</p>
<p>Regarding experience and feeling, this point resonates deeply with me. Many times before doing something or buying something, I would first seek experiences and advice from the internet or people in real life, then decide whether to do it or buy it. Most cases end up being discouraged, so I didn&rsquo;t try to do it in the end, which actually made me miss out on my own experiences and feelings. While previous experiences are important, only after we do something ourselves and have our own experience will we know if it suits us. So, boldly experience and feel everything that interests you.</p>
<h2 id="2-ichigo-ichie">2. Ichigo Ichie</h2>
<p>&ldquo;Ichigo ichie&rdquo; is a concept from Japanese tea ceremony, initially used in tea ceremonies to remind hosts and guests to cherish every tea gathering, because the time, scene, and participants of each tea ceremony cannot be replicated. The deeper meaning explains that each encounter is unique and may never happen again, so we should treat them with sincerity and cherish them.</p>
<p>Life is like ichigo ichie. On this life train that belongs to us, some people suddenly get on while others get off midway. The train keeps moving forward, the scenery and people outside the window quickly rush behind us row by row, mountains after mountains, waters after waters, the distant river flows east.</p>
<p>Cherish every encounter between people.</p>
<h2 id="3-this-world-is-a-huge-circle">3. This World is a Huge Circle</h2>
<p>For this section, I really don&rsquo;t know what else to write, so I found a diary entry I wrote one day in November. That day I went for a walk alone, exploring roads I had never taken before. The further I walked, the more lost I felt, thinking I would get lost, completely unable to tell directions. But I still kept walking forward, and unexpectedly arrived at a place I had been to but wasn&rsquo;t familiar with, so I walked around a bit and bought some QQ candy to take home, haha.</p>
<p>I quite like walking aimlessly, sometimes discovering unexpected delights. During my previous solo travels, I also applied this strategy - just walking randomly thinking I was lost and couldn&rsquo;t find my way out, but seeing different scenery: butterflies flying around garbage bins, a fierce-looking tabby cat sunbathing in warm sunlight, huge cacti, building architecture I had never seen before. Without relying on maps or having any purpose, just walking randomly also led me to tourist spots in the guidebook, after all this world is a huge circle. In any case, this is a nice travel experience for me, and I will probably continue doing so in the future.</p>
<p>So, perhaps, no matter how we walk, as long as we keep moving forward, destiny will lead us to the rivers we are meant to reach.</p>
<p>I&rsquo;ve rambled on so much, probably without much logic in it, and I don&rsquo;t know if anyone will see these things in my mind.</p>
<p>Wishing everyone good health and happy life.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>