<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Ryluiiwan</title>
    <link>http://localhost:11206/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Ryluiiwan</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:27:06 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:11206/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>S01E03: Starting a New Year, A Journal Entry of What I Did</title>
      <link>http://localhost:11206/en/2025/01/05/s01e03-starting-a-new-year-a-journal-entry-of-what-i-did/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jan 2025 14:27:06 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:11206/en/2025/01/05/s01e03-starting-a-new-year-a-journal-entry-of-what-i-did/</guid>
      <description>&amp;ldquo;Doing nothing&amp;rdquo; best describes this week&amp;rsquo;s state. Strangely, although I really enjoy this slightly boring state where I don&amp;rsquo;t have to do anything, I can&amp;rsquo;t contentedly enjoy it, always feeling that I should use this time to do something, that I can&amp;rsquo;t stop learning and improving. I constantly bounce between &amp;rsquo;let&amp;rsquo;s enjoy now and think later&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;regret doing nothing.&amp;rsquo; The brain can be deceptive, words are beautifully woven lies,</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S01E02: A Week of Lying Flat and Doing Sit-ups Repeatedly</title>
      <link>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/29/s01e02-a-week-of-lying-flat-and-doing-sit-ups-repeatedly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 14:26:42 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/29/s01e02-a-week-of-lying-flat-and-doing-sit-ups-repeatedly/</guid>
      <description>This month, I&amp;rsquo;ve been deeply troubled by noise from upstairs neighbors - heavy and sometimes sharp footsteps constantly coming from above. Whether at six or seven in the morning or midnight, you never know when that unique &amp;ldquo;noise&amp;rdquo; will suddenly appear, greatly reducing sleep quality. Already sensitive to sound, I&amp;rsquo;m becoming increasingly so, and am currently seeking various solutions.&#xA;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading Maugham&amp;rsquo;s The Painted Veil before bed. Though I thought it would take forever to finish, I completed it in just a few evenings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S01E01: Recent Days - A Journal Entry of Daily Life</title>
      <link>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/22/s01e01-recent-days-a-journal-entry-of-daily-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 17:07:52 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/22/s01e01-recent-days-a-journal-entry-of-daily-life/</guid>
      <description>Everything feels like it&amp;rsquo;s been put on fast-forward, and suddenly it&amp;rsquo;s late December. All that happened this year has started to blur, as if covered by a layer of dust. Getting older and addicted to fragmented information has left my brain rusty and locked, requiring occasional taps on the head to remember what year it is. Since my teenage years, I&amp;rsquo;ve worried about potentially developing Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s. Back then, I occasionally wrote on my little WeChat public account, creating a collection called &amp;ldquo;Memoirs of a Potential Alzheimer&amp;rsquo;s Patient,&amp;rdquo; where I would sporadically record things, hoping I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t forget.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>In November, I Started My 24th Year</title>
      <link>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/07/in-november-i-started-my-24th-year/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Dec 2024 12:11:08 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:11206/en/2024/12/07/in-november-i-started-my-24th-year/</guid>
      <description>Last month on the 8th was my 24th birthday. I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel much about it, nor did I have any sense of ceremony to celebrate. Even my mom forgot about my birthday. I feel that age is just a number to me - I can still eat ice cream, splash in puddles, observe little crabs in the supermarket, discover cute little things, and do things that elementary school kids do.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
